<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on Intellectual Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on Intellectual Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 16:29:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>FUDCon India 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fudcon-india-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 16:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fudcon-india-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I spent the last weekend of June at FUDCon India. FUDCon is the Fedora
Users and Developers Conference organized in different parts of the
world. The last FUDCon APAC that happened in India was in 2011 which i
could not attend because of my college. Being a Fedora user for 6 years
now I always wanted to attend one FUDCon. FUDCon APAC this year was held
at MIT College of Enginnering Pune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submitted talks on &amp;ldquo;fedmsg&amp;rdquo; and an 101 workshop on Flask. Flask being
one of the primary framework in most of the fedora-infra project. rtnpro
and I thought of introducing the guys with basics of Flask and how to
get started with Fedora Infra&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-0:b2a08ab57dfda47f8f3258e0c31249d0&#34;&gt;Day 0&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rtnpro and I reached Pune late night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-1:b2a08ab57dfda47f8f3258e0c31249d0&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the venue MITCoE pretty early at around 7:30am. I helped the
voluteer setups the standees. The event started with the key note by
Dennis Gilmore on &lt;strong&gt;Delivering Fedora for everything and everyone&lt;/strong&gt;. The
keynote was followed by Education Panel where the panel discussed on
open source and education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I headed to attend the talks on &lt;strong&gt;DNF&lt;/strong&gt;. Parag gave an
introduction to fedora&amp;rsquo;s new package manager and how it was architecture
was re-built&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaidik in his talk on &lt;strong&gt;Vagrant for Effective DevOps Culture&lt;/strong&gt; talked on
how Wingify utilizes vagrant for setting up their dev environment close
to the prod environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the talk I headed over to the speaker&amp;rsquo;s lounge and worked on my
talk presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last talk that I attended was &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to networkd&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-2:b2a08ab57dfda47f8f3258e0c31249d0&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started with a really good talk by Jiri Eishchmann on &lt;strong&gt;Present
and Future of Fedora Workstation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He discussed on what all it takes to ship a Fedora Workstation. He also
told that MP3 patent expires this September, so Linux distributions like
Fedora can start playing MP3s by default. This was a good news. Later
after the talk I discussed with him the issues of gaming in Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk was followed by tuxology talk on &lt;strong&gt;Kernel and Userspace Tracing
with LTTng and Friends&lt;/strong&gt; and rejy&amp;rsquo;s talk on &lt;em&gt;Be Secure with SELinux
Gyan&lt;/em&gt;. Need to say the talk and the presentation was really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nigelb&amp;rsquo;s talked on how to start contributing to Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I had my talk lined up. I spoke on the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Fedora Infrastructure leverages the Fedmsg(Federated Message
Bus)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Fedmsg works?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects on top of Fedmsg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to start working on Fedmsg?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the hallway I spoke with juhp on how to get started with Haskell and
the projects in fedora that I can start helping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my talk I attended the talk on &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started with IOT
development using Fedora on ARM&lt;/strong&gt; by Rajesh and &lt;strong&gt;Achieving Community
Goals with Fedora&lt;/strong&gt; by Tenzin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the conference, speakers and volunteers headed for the FUDPub. The
FUDPub was total fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A re-quote from FUDPub 2011 &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Best FUDPub Ever&amp;rdquo; - Jared Smith&lt;/strong&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3:b2a08ab57dfda47f8f3258e0c31249d0&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started at the speaker lounge with me writing a Telegram bot to
push the fedmsg messages to the application. Praveen Kumar and I worked
some some vim and flask thingy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I moved over for the workshop. rtnpro and I gave a Flask 101
workshop and how to search for easyfixes in the fedora infra. Due to
lack to time we could needed to skip a few topics. But the workshop
turned out to a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post lunch I created my GPG key. I created many of them in the past but
never kept a backup of any :( I got to know what&amp;rsquo;s actually is a
key-signing party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally Rupali gave a thank you speech to all those who made FUDCon
India 2015 successful. Kudos to all the participants, speakers and
volunteers who made this event a grand success. In the end - I am really
happy to be part of such a great event where I got to meet so many
fedora contributors and learnt so many things in a matter of three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pics coming soon :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon India 2013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pycon-india-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pycon-india-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-month:c30e63d7fb5ff4d7cbb348626b70870b&#34;&gt;Python Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended last year’s PyCon India, while in college and it was a great
experience. After shifting to Bangalore this year, I thought why not
volunteer Pycon India this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a regular attendee to the Pycon India meetings held at the Goibibo
office at M.G.Road. This year it was thought to celebrate the month of
August Python Month as a part of PyCon this year. As a part of Python
Month, volunteers would go to various college across the country to
evangelize and teach python to college students.I personally went to two
colleges, BNM Institute of Technology and Reva Institute of Technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pycon-india-2013:c30e63d7fb5ff4d7cbb348626b70870b&#34;&gt;PyCon India 2013&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As i was volunteering Pycon this year, I was given the task for inventory
management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited hasgeek’s office often and learnt to setup the registration desk. I helped out with Illiyas and Bibhas. We moved the inventory to NIMHANS
Convention Centre, where PyCon was held this year. We worked the night
before to get things running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-day-29-august-2013:c30e63d7fb5ff4d7cbb348626b70870b&#34;&gt;First Day, 29 August 2013&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day was the workshop day. We left for the first day early. As i
reached the venue, Konark Modi told me to assist the workshop trainer in
AUDI 1. The trainer was none other that rtnpro giving his workshop on
testing. AUDI 1 was coordinated by me and Santosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;second-day-30-august-2013-third-day-1-september-2013:c30e63d7fb5ff4d7cbb348626b70870b&#34;&gt;Second Day, 30 August 2013 - Third Day, 1 September 2013&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crowd for PyCon India started pouring in on the second day and it was
huge. There was a huge Q at the registration desk. The main event started
with the keynote by Kiran Jonnalagadda. After the keynote I headed towards
AUDI 2 where i was assiting for the rest of the PyCon. Though, I could not
switch over and go to see the other talk but i guess the talks in AUDI 2
were the best. This year we also saw the largest participation from our
LUG, Durgapur Linux Users Group(dgplug). We had a LUG meeting were we
discussed on the past, present and the future of dgplug. We got ourselves a LUG photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day, Kenneth gave the keynote speech. He is the author of the
python-requests module. This year PyCon was bigger and better than last
year. Being a food junkie, food comes in my top priority list and we were
served well at PyCon. More than event, i was glad to meet countless number of people during PyCon India and Python Month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to all the organizers, volunteers and participants to make PyCon
India 2013 a huge success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-pycon:c30e63d7fb5ff4d7cbb348626b70870b&#34;&gt;After PyCon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 2nd September, i left for a one day trip to Mysore with Kushal, rtnpro and Kenneth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>