<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nitdgplug on Intellectual Web</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nitdgplug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nitdgplug on Intellectual Web</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 01:45:03 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nitdgplug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mukti 2014</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mukti-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 01:45:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mukti-2014/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mkti.in/&#34;&gt;Mukti 2014&lt;/a&gt; is the annual national level technical
symposium on Free and Open Source Software of the GNU/Linux Users’ Group
NIT Durgapur held from 31st January - 2nd February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been attending Mukti for last four years. Unlike, the previous
years when i usually attended Mukti as a student participant, this year
I attended Mukti as a guest speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-0-30th-january-2014:fe52ebdd6d5eb6c60ad2d67c95ea3093&#34;&gt;Day 0 (30th January 2014)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a hectic travel from Bangalore to Durgapur via Kolkata. TMC called
of the largest Brigade Rally in Kolkata on the very day. The bus i was
travelling from Kolkata Airport to Howrah station dropped me at an
unknown location. I somehow dragged myself and my luggage to station.
The condition at the station was worse, packed compartments including
the reserved ones and people fighting for their seats. After a big
quarrel, I somehow got my seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sayantanfoto.blogspot.in/&#34;&gt;Sayantan a.k.a kenzo450D&lt;/a&gt; came over
to the station to pick me up. I reached NIT Durgapur at around 9pm. I
did a overnight stay at kenzo&amp;rsquo;s hostel room. &lt;a href=&#34;http://ciypro.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Chandan
Kumar&lt;/a&gt; arrived early morning the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-1-31st-january-2014:fe52ebdd6d5eb6c60ad2d67c95ea3093&#34;&gt;Day 1 (31st January 2014)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a typical winter morning. Living in bangalore for sometime now, I
was not accustomed with the winter. I was actually feeling good. The
event started at around 10:30AM. Chandan went over the the auditorium to
set up the system for his evening session on OpenStack. I gathered some
of the students in a classroom and told them the importance of
contributing to Open Source. Chandan joined in after sometime. We
discussed how contributing helped us and more importantly why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t
we neglect the subjects in our curricullum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chandan gave a session on OpenStack, explaining the various components
and setting it up on local maching. Later that night we went over for a
dinner with the organizing committee, there we met with Shahid Farooqui.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-2-1st-february-2014:fe52ebdd6d5eb6c60ad2d67c95ea3093&#34;&gt;Day 2 (1st February 2014)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event started off with my workshop on building webapps with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://flask.pocoo.org/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; . The workshop started off with a chaos
with no system having Flask, virtualenv and git installed. I, along with
the committee took quick steps and installed the pre-requisite on the
systems. I discussed with them how Flask plays an important role in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fedoraproject.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;. The workshop went pretty well. The
audience was around 60 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sayanchowdhury/mukti-flask-101&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sayanchowdhury/mukti-flask-101&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sayanchowdhury/mukti-flask-101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went over to an auditorium along with some enthusiastic
students, Chandan and I gave them a task to build an IRC bot using the
Twisted framework. At a parallel workshop on &amp;ldquo;Building Firefox OS apps&amp;rdquo;,
we met &lt;a href=&#34;http://kaustavdm.in/&#34;&gt;Kaustav&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://birajkarmakar.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Biraj&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosswithumesh.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Umesh&lt;/a&gt;, Jai and Gaurab. We went
for a dinner later that night will all the guest speakers and
organizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3-2nd-february-2014:fe52ebdd6d5eb6c60ad2d67c95ea3093&#34;&gt;Day 3 (2nd February 2014)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Day 3, I coordinated in the Mozilla workshop in the beginning. Later
that day we hacked on our projects with some of the students messing
with the IRC bot. In the evening, at the lightening talk session I
showed the students how contribute to various Open Source organization.
It was kind of a demo version of this &lt;a href=&#34;http://sayanchowdhury.dgplug.org/posts/how-to-get-started-with-open-source.html&#34;&gt;blog
post&lt;/a&gt;.
I showed the attendees the various websites to start contributing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the complete Mukti team specially Anish, Vivek and Sayantan,
who did a commendable job. Hope Mukti 2015 is bigger and better :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images copyright: Sayantan Datta&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>